Senior Software Engineer – Frontend

Purpose driven, and collaborative Sr Frontend Software Engineer, with 10+ years of remote development experience. Dedicated to stakeholder satisfaction and clean, elegantly functional software.

I've been described as an asset to every team I join. I bring both deep technical knowledge and a willingness to jump in and help. My customer focus/product mindset is one of my biggest strengths. I've often been requested by name by our professional services customers because of my attention to detail and focus on helping the customer achieve their vision. My primary strength is in the frontend, but I've never had a purely frontend position. I am adaptable and learn quickly.

Highlights of Expertise/Stacks/Languages/Frameworks

- Engineering of code, React/TS/JS/HTML/CSS
- PR Review
- Testing and QA

- Discussion of requirements/strategies
- Technical planning and design
- UX design and implementation

Career Experience

Equity Prime Mortgage, Atlanta, GA - Fully remote from Oakland, CA, USA Mortgage loan, TPO portal, SaaS application.

Senior Software Engineer (Dec. 2023 to present)

Primarily concerned with EPMX, engineering the React, Typescript front-end, UI/UX implementation and NodeJS/Express/MongoDB and encompass, back-end.

Project Link: https://epmexperience.com

- Guided technical design and established code standards for the new version of the front-end application, ensuring the new app had a scalable, maintainable modern codebase.
- Engineered seamless fallbacks, allowing the module federation of components into the existing app for immediate release of new features that were only available under the new architecture.
- Transmuted confusing code through iterative refactoring into clean, reusable components using React hooks, cutting 75% of development time.
- Achieved 80%+ test coverage, utilizing husky to automate testing in Jest and testing-library/react before the code left the local environment, and again on GitHub.
- Recognized company wide, on 2 separate occasions, for quick and flawless implementation of high visibility, front end changes including a total re-brand.

Home Point Financial Corporation, Ann Arbor, MI - Fully remote from Oakland, CA, USA Mortgage loan, TPO portal, SaaS application serving 10k active broker firms with 90k users.

Senior Software Engineer (Feb. 2018 to Jul. 2023)

Primarily concerned with The Point, engineering the React, Typescript, Less, front-end, UI/UX implementation, and minor adjustments to the C#, MS SOL and encompass back-end.

- Guided technical design and established code standards for the new version of the front-end application, ensuring the new app had a scalable, maintainable modern codebase.
- Engineered seamless fallbacks, allowing the module federation of components into the existing app for immediate release of new features that were only available under the new architecture.

Dragon Messmer Page 2

• Transmuted confusing code through iterative refactoring into clean, reusable components using React hooks, cutting 75% of development time.

- Achieved 80%+ test coverage, utilizing husky to automate testing in Jest and testing-library/react before the code left the local environment, and again on GitHub.
- Recognized company wide, on 2 separate occasions, for quick and flawless implementation of high visibility, front end changes including a total re-brand.

UniteU, Pittsford, NY - Fully remote from Rochester, NY, USA

Provided proprietary templated, ecommerce sites/admin panels, before Magento and Shopify took over the industry. We were one of the first to utilize responsive design to enable use on mobile phones.

Staff Technologist (Jan. 2012 to Feb. 2018)

Collaborated with clients, product managers, and other developers to create and customize ASP.NET ecommerce sites, utilizing Sass and jQuery.

- Preferred developer of demanding, high visibility clients (Nancy Meyer, Joes Jeans, Golf Galaxy) resulting in retention of important customers.
- Provided the company a competitive edge by creating a fully responsive, and backward compatible template, using HTML5 and CSS3 (Sass/SCSS).
- Transformed customer relations with Hickey Freeman through implementation of challenging animated background design.
- Delighted Hyde Park Jewelers with pixel perfect design implementation, saving the account.
- Delivered header with menus animation to the City Sports website.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer - Gracenote, Emeryville, CA

Software Engineer/Artist – Skullyflower.com, personal project/playground Oakland, CA

Education & Credentials

Monroe Community College, Rochester, NY

Accounting - AAS - 2010 (in response to 2008 crash)

Professional Development: Certificates and Trainings:

- Continuously learning and honing: LinkedIn learning, Pluralsight Skills, Code Academy, YouTube and other trainings, tutorials and reference materials.
- MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional, Microsoft 2014
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft 2014

Technical Proficiencies: JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, REST APIs, Redux, Webpack, Vite, jQuery, SCSS, LESS, Docker, GitHub, Azure, Git, Storybook, Zeplin, Figma